Guide to the Actors' Equity Association Records WAG.011
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Actors' Equity Association Records
1913-2007
1913-1991
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Actors' Equity Association
Bruyr, Robert J.
WAG.011
369.25 Linear Feet in 378 boxes
1 videocassette
The Actors' Equity Association (AEA) is the labor union of professional theatrical performers and stage managers. It was founded in 1913 but did not gain full recognition as the bargaining agent for actors until the historic strike of 1919. The AEA negotiates contracts and agreements, arbitrates contract disputes, regulates the importation of alien actors, regulates charges by theatrical agents, provides a pension plan and welfare fund, and otherwise assists the theatrical industry. The Actors' Equity records contain materials for the period 1913-2007. This guide describes records covering the first seventy-six years of the union's history, including constitutions, by-laws and rule books; early records, general files, membership files, contract files, claims files, photographs, ephemera, correspondence with other unions, guilds and federations, and one videocassette.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by the Actors' Equity Association, 1982. The accession number associated with this gift is 1982.007.
One VHS tapes was donated by Robert J. Bruyr, 1998. The accession number associated with this item is 2018.052.
The thesis in Box 363 was found in the repository in 2014. The accession number associated with this item is 2014.037.
Conditions Governing Access
Series IV: Membership Files is closed to patrons until 2028. The remainder of the collection is open without restrictions.
Historical Note
The Actors' Equity Association collection is the largest of several collections at the Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives devoted to labor unionism in the performing arts. Taken together, these materials comprise the largest archival resource on this subject in the nation. This body of material provides a wealth of information on the history of the American commercial stage and on labor relations in many branches of the entertainment industry.
The Actors' Equity Association is the union of professional legitimate stage actors and stage managers. It was founded in New York City in May 1913, by 112 actors committed to fighting the arbitrary work rules and low wages then prevalent in the American theatre. In July 1919, the American Federation of Labor chartered the Associated Actors and Artistes of America (known as the 4A's). Equity, with a membership of 2,700 was its largest component. With the support of the musicians' and stagehands' unions, a major strike for recognition followed in August 1919. The strike occurred in eight cities and closed thirty-seven productions while preventing sixteen others from opening. This "revolt of the actors" swelled Equity's membership, instigated the formation of the Chorus Equity Association (CEA), and won a strong five-year contract between the union and the Producing Managers Association. From the beginning, Equity fought for the principal of arbitration of contractual disputes. From the beginning, Equity's headquarters have been in New York City; it also maintains branch offices in Los Angeles, San Francisco and Chicago. Equity is governed by its delegate Council, elected by the membership.
In 1924, Equity achieved its goal of closed shop agreements and continued to make basic improvements in actors' contracts. Bonding provisions guaranteed salaries and transportation (1924); restrictions were placed on alien actors' activity in American theatres (1928); franchising of agents was established (1929); a minimum wage was guaranteed (1933); and minimum rehearsal expenses were paid (1935). Under the auspices of the 4A's, Equity-affiliated screen actors attempted to organize the burgeoning motion picture industry in the 1920s, but were frustrated in their efforts. In 1934, the 4A's jurisdiction over screen actors was handed over to the newly formed Screen Actors Guild.
From 1950 on, Equity began to organize the industrial shows field and subsequently regional, children's and dinner theatres. Chorus and Actors' Equity merged in 1955. A safe and sanitary code for backstage working conditions was established, and minimum rehearsal payments were established. The Pension and Welfare Plan was achieved only after a strike -- the twelve-day Broadway Blackout of 1960.
In the field of civil rights, the union initiated a boycott of segregated theatres in 1947, targeting the National Theatre in Washington, DC. Subsequently Equity's policies against segregation were extended to all theatres which discriminated against either performers or patrons with regard to race, color or creed. In recent years this principle has been extended to include discrimination on sexual preference or political persuasion or belief. In 1982, Equity adopted an affirmative action policy to increase employment opportunities for ethnic minorities and women.
Equity's uncompromising support of its members who were affected by blacklisting and other forms of official and informal persecution during the McCarthy era was almost unique in the entertainment industry and among labor unions in general. On September 28, 1951, after several members had been blacklisted and denied the opportunity to work in television, Equity's Council passed a resolution stating that blacklisting was "hostile to the fundamental purposes of this Association, and that Actors' Equity will act to the fullest of its capacities in defense of its members."
Equity's union work has always extended beyond contractual jurisdiction in actors' lives. Benevolent projects are at the heart of much of the union's functions. Actors' Equity Foundation has a theatre grants program, while a credit union provides credit and financial services to members. The Foundation also aids theatres suffering unforeseen catastrophes, contributes to the Actors' Fund of America, the charitable arm of the theatrical unions, and funds certain worthy theatrical projects. Equity also assists Save the Theatres, Inc., a not-for-profit body whose purpose is the preservation of important old theatre houses.
Sources:
Alfred Harding, The Revolt of the Actors(New York: William Morrow and Co., 1929).
Scope and Content Note
The Actors' Equity Association records consists of all of the earliest records of the organization (1913-1929), as well as general files, membership records, contract files, claims, correspondence with other unions, guilds and federations, photographs, ephemera, and one vidocassette. The date range for these materilas is 1913-2007.
The early records of Actors' Equity include materials created by or relating to a number of luminaries of the theatre, including W.C. Fields, Helen Hayes, Fanny Brice, Eddie Cantor, Florenz Ziegfeld, Basil Rathbone, Maurice Evans, Anita Loos and many others. These famous names constitute only a few of the actors, directors, producers, agents, and other theatrical personalities whose work is chronicled in the Equity collection. This material offers a vivid glimpse into the lives and stage careers that have made up twentieth-century American theatre. The General Files series includes documentation of the presidencies of Ralph Bellamy, Frederick O'Neal and Theodore Bikel, as well as the issues of agents' commissions, pensions, health benefits and housing.
Arrangement
The collection consists of ten series:
I. Constitutions, By-laws and Rule Books, 1914-1979
II. Foundations of Actors' Equity, 1913-1929
III. General Files
IV. Membership Files, Dec. 1913-1978
V. Contracts/Agreements/Codes
VI. Claims, 1915-1986
VII. Other Unions/Guilds/Federations
VIII: Oversize/Scrapbooks
IX: Archived Website
X: Photographs and Ephemera
Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
American Guild of Variety Artists Records (WAG 95)
Actors' Fund Records (WAG 36)
Associated Actors and Artistes of America Records (WAG 110)
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Custodial History
The archived website was migrated from the California Digital Library's Web Archiving Service to the Internet Archive's Archive-It Service in November 2015. The link to California Digital Library was removed in October 2017.
Actors -- United States.; Actresses -- United States.; Actors -- Labor unions -- United States.; Theater -- United States -- History.; Blacklisting of entertainers.; Associated Actors and Artistes of America; Chorus Equity Association; Television Authority (TVA); Bellamy, Ralph, 1904-1991; O'Neal, Frederick, 1905-1992; Bikel, Theodore; Derwent, Clarence, 1884-1959; Dullzell, Paul; Gillmore, Frank; Harding, Alfred, 1892-1969; Actors' Equity Association; Bruyr, Robert J.
- Series I: Constitutions, By-laws and Rule Books, 1914-1978
  Scope and Content Note
  This series is comprised of Constitutions and By-laws, 1914-1970s, and Rule Books for many different kinds of productions (industrial shows, Off-Broadway, stock, etc.), 1924-1979.
  Arrangement
  Files are arranged alphabetically by topic, and chronologically within topics.
  - Chorus Equity Association (CEA) Constitution and By-Laws, 1926, 1939, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Constitution/Rule Book, Dec 1914 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Constitution and By-laws, 1920s (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Constitution and By-laws, 1930s (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Constitution and By-Laws, 1940s (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Constitution and By-laws, 1950s (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Constitution and By-laws, 1960s (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Constitution and By-laws, 1970s (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Constitution and By-laws, 1980s (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Constitution and By-laws, 1990s (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Digest of Minimum Salaries/Equity Members' Digest, 1970s (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Equity Handbook, 1950s, 1960s (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Rule Books: Bay Area Theatres (BAT), 1989-1991, 2003-2006 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Rule Books: British Equity Subsidised Repretory, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Rule Books: Business Theatre, 1988-2000 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Rule Books: Cabaret, 1984-2001 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Rule Books: Casino Agreement, 2001-2005 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Rule Books: Chicago Area theaters/Chicagoland Off-Loop, 1981-1995 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Rule Books: Children's Theatre, 1969-1975 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Rule Books: Dinner Theatre, 1973-1985 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Rule Books: Dinner Theatre, 1985-1998 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Rule Books: Expo '67, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Rule Books: Funded Non-Profit Theatre Code, 1990s (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Rule Books: Hollywood Area Theatres, 1959, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Rule Books: Hollywood Area/Bay Area Theatres (HAT/BAT), 1970-1976 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Rule Books: Hollywood Area/Bay Area Theatres (HAT/BAT>, 1978-1987 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Rule Books: Industrial Shows, 1956, 1958, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Rule Books: Industrial Shows, 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Rule Books: Little Theatres (and Schools), 1944 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Rule Books: Off-Broadway, 1967-1987 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Rule Books: Off-Broadway, 1987-2005 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Rule Books: Production, 1968-1974, 1977-1989 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Rule Books: Production, 1989-2004 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Rule Books: Production/BV [Buena Vista] TVI, 1996-2000 (Box 1A, Folder 1)
  - Rule Books: Production/Livent, 1996-2000 (Box 1A, Folder 2)
  - Rule Books: Resident Theatres (LORT), 1966-1978 (Box 1A, Folder 3)
  - Rule Books: Resident Theatres (LORT), 1978-2002 (Box 1A, Folder 4)
  - Rule Books: Showcase Code, 1969-1971, 1988-2000 (Box 1A, Folder 5)
  - Rule Books: Small Professional Theatres (SPT), 1992-2007 (Box 1A, Folder 6)
  - Rule Books: Stock, 1951-1956 (Box 1A, Folder 7)
  - Rule Books: Stock, Dramatic, 1957-1966 (Box 1A, Folder 8)
  - Rule Books: Stock, Indoor Musical, 1966-1981 (Box 1A, Folder 9)
  - Rule Books: Stock, Musical, 1957-1963 (Box 1A, Folder 10)
  - Rule Books: Stock, Non-Resident Dramatic (COST), 1969-1995 (Box 1A, Folder 11)
  - Rule Books: Stock, Outdoor Musical, 1963-1969, 1979-1991 (Box 1A, Folder 12)
  - Rule Books: Stock, Resident Dramatic (CORST), 1966-1983 (Box 1A, Folder 13)
  - Rule Books: Stock, Resident Dramatic (CORST), 1984-1997 (Box 1A, Folder 14)
  - Rule Books: Stock, Resident Musical (RMTA), 1984-1986, 1993-1996 (Box 1A, Folder 15)
  - Rule Books: Summer Stock, 1938, 1948 (Box 1A, Folder 16)
  - Rule Books: Theatre for Young Audiences (TYA), 1975-2002 (Box 1A, Folder 17)
  - Rule Books: University Resident Theatres, 1981-2007 (Box 1A, Folder 18)
  - Rule Books: Walt Disney World, 1990-2004 (Box 1A, Folder 19)
  - Rule Books: Western Region Community Non-Profit, 2000-2006 (Box 1A, Folder 20)
  - Rule Books: World's Fair (galley proof), 1964-1965 (Box 1A, Folder 21)
  - Rules and Regulations, Governing the Employment of, 1970s (Box 1A, Folder 22)
  - Rules: Bus Tours, 1958 (Box 1A, Folder 23)
  - Rules: Code for 'Actors Workshops, Scene Classes', 1962 (Box 1A, Folder 24)
  - Rules: Extracts of Rules for Musical Productions, 1958 (Box 1A, Folder 25)
  - Rules: [Governing] Employment, 1924 (Box 1A, Folder 26)
  - Rules [Governing] Relating to Employment, 1930s (Box 1A, Folder 27)
  - Rules Governing Employment, 1940s (Box 1A, Folder 28)
  - Rules Governing Employment, 1950s (Box 1A, Folder 29)
  - Rules Governing Employment, 1960s (Box 1A, Folder 30)
  - Rules Governing Employment in Ballet Companies in Canada, 1961 (Box 1A, Folder 31)
  - Rules Governing Rule A, 1958 (Box 1A, Folder 32)
  - Rules: 'Off-Broadway Ammendments', 1959 (Box 1A, Folder 33)
- Series II: Foundations of Actors' Equity, 1913-1933
  This series is comprised of all the extant records of the union's earliest years (1913-1929), including agreements, auditors' reports, contracts, correspondence of AEA officers and representatives, records of membership meetings and miscellaneous subject files. Also included in this series are a group of autobiographical notebooks of AEA President Clarence Derwent and an extensive group of research files, notes and typescript drafts for Alfred Harding's historical study of the early years of Actors' Equity, The Revolt of the Actors(1929).
  Files are arranged alphabetically by topic.
  - Actors' Fidelity League: Fidelity (newsletter), 1921 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Actors' Fidelity League: Member's Book, 1920 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Agency Policy, 1928-1930 (Box 2, Folder 2A)
  - Agreement and Pledge, 1919 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Agreement and Pledge signed by Members, 1917-1919 (Flat-file 1, Drawer 15, Folder 1)
  - Agreement: Managers Protective Association, 1924, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Agreement: Producing Managers Association, 1919 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Agreement: Shubert's, 1921 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - American Committee for Relief of German Children, 1924 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - "Articles of Agreement, Constitution and By-Laws of the Actors' Equity Association" [Draft?], undated [1913?] (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Child Labor Laws, undated [to 1919] (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Chorus Equity Association (CEA): Agreement between Managers Protective Association (MPA) and CEA, 1924 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Chorus Equity Association: Agreement between MPA and CEA, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Chorus Equity Association: Agreement between Producing Managers Association (PMA) and CEA, 1919 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Chorus Equity Association: Auditor's Reports, 1922-1923 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Chorus Equity Association: Auditor's Reports, 1924-1925 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Chorus Equity Association: Auditor's Reports, 1926-1927 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Chorus Equity Association: Auditor's Reports, 1928-1929 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Chorus Equity Association: Chorus of Equity Song, 1920 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Chorus Equity Association: Contract between Mae Chesterly and Dalton Enterprises, 1919 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Chorus Equity Association: Contracts, 1920s (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Chorus Equity Association: Correspondence I, 1919 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Chorus Equity Association: Correspondence II, 1919 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Chorus Equity Association: Deputy Report, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Chorus Equity Association: Employment Lists, 1921 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Chorus Equity Association: Employment Lists, 1922 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Chorus Equity Association: Members Information Booklet, undated (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Chorus Equity Association: Minutes, Aug 19, 1919-Aug 18, 1920 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Chorus Equity Association: Minutes, Sep 10, 1920-Aug 31, 1921 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Chorus Equity, Association: Minutes, Sep 14, 1921-Apr 30, 1924 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Collective Bargaining by Actors: U.S. Dept. of Labor, 1926 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Contracts: Additions, Addendums, 1924 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Contracts: Blank, 1923 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Contracts: Blank, 1924 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Contracts: Blank, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Contracts: Blank, 1926 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Contracts: Blank, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Contracts: Blank, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Contracts: Blank, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Contracts: Blank, non-AEA, 1920s (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Correspondence: AEA with Mesurac, Frank (Auditor), 1924 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Correspondence: AEA Executives, Reps, 1924 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Correspondence: AEA Executives, Reps with 'F', 1924 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Correspondence: AEA Execs with Foreign Companies, 1924 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Correspondence: AEA Executives, Reps with 'G-H', 1924 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Correspondence: AEA Executives, Reps with 'J-K', 1924 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Correspondence: AEA Executives, Reps with 'L', 1924 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Correspondence: AEA Executives, Reps with 'M', 1924 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Correspondence: AEA Executives, Reps with Legislation, 1923-1924 (Box 2A, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: AEA Executives, Reps with Members, 1920s (Box 2A, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: AEA Executives, Reps with Other (non-performing) Unions, 1924 (Box 2A, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: Gillmore, Frank with IATSE, 1924 (Box 2A, Folder 4)
  - Deputy Reports, 1921-1929 (Box 2A, Folder 5)
  - Deputy Reports: Bound Volumes of CEA and AEA Reports for 1923, 1924, 1926, 1923-1926 (Box 2A)
  - Deputy Reports: Bound Volumes of CEA and AEA Reports for 1927, 1928, 1930, 1931, 1932, 1933, 1927-1933 (Box 368)
  - Derwent, Clarence: Autobiographical Notebooks Entries 1-112, 1903-1929 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Derwent, Clarence: Autobiographical Notebooks Entries 113-200, 1903-1929 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Derwent, Clarence: Autobiographical Notebooks Entries 201-260, 1903-1929 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Derwent, Clarence: Autobiographical Notebooks Entries 261-340, 1903-1929 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Derwent, Clarence: Autobiographical Notebooks Entries 341-423, 1903-1929 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Derwent, Clarence: Contracts, 1915, 1921, 1923 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Derwent, Clarence: Loose Clips, 1903-1929 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Duncan, Augustin: Contracts, 1971, 1921 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Emerson, Mr. & Mrs. John (Anita Loos): Personal Correspondence, 1921-1933 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Equity Ball: Programs, 1924, 1929 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Equity Ball: Ticket Receipt, 1921 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Equity Players, Inc., 1923-1924 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Equity Shop: Instructions, 1921 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Equity Shop: Petitions, 1920, 1936 (Flat-file 2, Drawer 7, Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Equity Shop: PMA Agreement Press Releases, 1924 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Federated Bank of New York, 1923-1924 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Gillmore, Frank: Memos to Representatives, 1921-1923 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Gillmore, Frank: Memos to Representatives, 1924-1926 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Gillmore, Frank: Memos to Representatives, 1927-1929 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Gillmore, Frank: Speeches, Hollywood Meetings, Jun 1929 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Gillmore, Frank: Speeches, Hollywood Meetings, Jul 1929 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Gillmore, Frank: Speeches, Hollywood Meetings, Aug 1929 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Gordon, Leon: Christmas Hampers, 1924 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Gordon, William C.: Correspondence re: Advertising in Equity, 1924 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Green Room Club, 1924 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Hackett, James K., 1924 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Harding, Alfred and Stewart, Grant: Correspondence, 1922-1929 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Irwin, Mike: Incident, 1923-1924 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Lloyd, Harry E., 1922-1924 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Lowenthal and Munns Correspondence, 1922, 1924 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Macloon, Louis, 1924 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Manhattan Opera House, 1924 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Membership Forms, 1920s (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Membership Meetings, 1913 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Membership Meetings, 1914 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Membership Meetings, 1915 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Membership Meetings, 1916 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Membership Meetings, 1917 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Membership Meetings, 1919 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Membership Meetings: Copy of Minutes, Nov 3, 1919 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Membership Meetings, 1920 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Membership Meetings, 1921 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Membership Meetings, 1922 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Membership Meetings, 1923 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Membership Meetings, 1924 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Membership Meetings, 1925 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Membership Meetings, 1926 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Membership Meetings, 1927 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Membership Meetings, 1928 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Membership Meetings, 1929 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Methodist Church: Amusement Clause, 1924 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Minutes: Founding, Jan 1913-Apr 1913 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Minutes: Founding, May 1913-Sep 1913 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Minutes: Founding: Original Binder, 1913 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Mitchell, Grant Correspondence, 1924 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Motion Picture Industry, 1920s (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Notices/Form Letters, 1922, 1924 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Pilgrimage Play, Los Angeles, 1920 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Producing Managers' Association (PMA): Letter to IATSE, Aug 16, 1919 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Project for a National Theatre Foundation, undated [1920s?] (Box 4, Folder 16A)
  - Revolt of the Actors by Alfred Harding: Research Documents, 1920s (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Revolt of the Actors: AEA Chronology, 1920s (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Revolt of the Actors: AEA Mtg, Chicago, Feb 1, 1919, 1920s (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Revolt of the Actors: Reports, 1919, 1920s (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Revolt of the Actors: Notes on the Strike I, 1920s (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Revolt of the Actors: Notes on the Strike II, 1920s (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Revolt of the Actors: Notes on the Strike III, 1920s (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Revolt of the Actors: Lists, Strike Committees, Meetings, 1920s (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Revolt of the Actors: Notes on Elections, 1920s (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Revolt of the Actors: Suits and Injunctions, 1920s (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Revolt of the Actors: Notes on AEA Minutes, 1920s (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Revolt of the Actors: Notes on AEA Minutes, 1920s (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Revolt of the Actors: Notes/American Theatre History, 1920s (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Revolt of the Actors: Notes, 1920s (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Revolt of the Actors: Notes, 1920s (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Revolt of the Actors: Notes, 1920s (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Revolt of the Actors: Notes, 1920s (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Revolt of the Actors: Notes, 1920s (Box 4, Folder 34)